[
    {
      "questionNo": "Q1",
      "question": "Which of the following is a statement?",
      "options": [
        "“What time is it?”",
        "“The sun rises in the east.”",
        "“Please close the door.”",
        "“Are you coming to the party?”"
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "questionNo": "Q2",
      "question": "What is the form of a conditional statement?",
      "options": [
        "“If P, then Q.”",
        "“P and Q.”",
        "“P or Q.”",
        "“Not P and not Q.”"
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "questionNo": "Q3",
      "question": "Identify the antecedent in:<br> “If it rains, then the ground will be wet.”",
      "options": [
        "It does not rain.",
        "The ground will be wet.",
        "It rains.",
        "The ground is dry."
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "questionNo": "Q4",
      "question": "What is the contrapositive of: <br>“If the car is red, then it is fast”?",
      "options": [
        "If it is not red, then it is not fast.",
        "If it is not fast, then it is not red.",
        "If it is fast, then it is red.",
        "If the car is not red, then it is fast."
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "questionNo": "Q5",
      "question": "Which of the following demonstrates the converse of the conditional statement <br>“If a number is even, then it is divisible by 2”?",
      "options": [
        "If a number is divisible by 2, then it is even.",
        "If a number is not even, then it is not divisible by 2.",
        "If a number is not divisible by 2, then it is not even.",
        "If a number is even, then it is not divisible by 2."
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "questionNo": "Q6",
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT a valid logical statement?",
      "options": [
        "“I think, therefore I am.”",
        "“7 is greater than 3.”",
        "“Perhaps we are not alone in the universe.”",
        "“Water freezes at 0 degrees Celsius.”"
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "questionNo": "Q7",
      "question": "Which condition is logically equivalent to “If a tree is a pine, then it is an evergreen”?",
      "options": [
        "If a tree is not an evergreen, then it is not a pine.",
        "If a tree is an evergreen, then it is a pine.",
        "If a tree is not a pine, then it is not an evergreen.",
        "If a tree is a pine, then it is not an evergreen."
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "questionNo": "Q8",
      "question": "What can be inferred from the statement “If there is smoke, there is fire”?",
      "options": [
        "If there is no fire, there is no smoke.",
        "If there is fire, there is smoke.",
        "If there is no smoke, there is fire.",
        "If there is smoke, there is no fire."
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "questionNo": "Q9",
      "question": "What does the statement “If the light is green, then you can drive” imply?",
      "options": [
        "If you cannot drive, the light is green.",
        "If you can drive, the light is not green.",
        "If the light is not green, you cannot drive.",
        "If you can drive, the light is not green."
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "questionNo": "Q10",
      "question": "If a number is divisible by 4, then it is even.<br> Which of the following statements is the converse of the original statement?",
      "options": [
        "If a number is not divisible by 4, then it is not even.",
        "If a number is even, then it is divisible by 4.",
        "If a number is not even, then it is divisible by 4.",
        "If a number is not even, then it is not divisible by 4."
      ],
      "correct": 1
    }
  ]
  